# Mayank Gupta

# Senior Software Engineer



techfreakworm 🔇

https://mayankgupta.in

Application Developer with more than two years of experience in Web and Desktop application Development. Involved in development and testing of new features/bugs. Currently working on Deep Learning based analytics web app .to predict Customer Churn.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Cyber Group India Pvt. Ltd.

04/2019 - Present

Noida, India

 Developed deep learning model, contributed in analytics microservice and analysis dashboard made in Angular 8.

## **Software Engineer**

Cyber Group India Pvt. Ltd.

07/2017 - 03/2019

Noida, India

- Developed and tested enhancement and bugs in Web API in Energy Domain Email Campaigns.
- Fixed bugs and tested changes in Energy domain web applications and VSTO excel plugin
- Wrote preprocessing and AI scripts for Customer Churn insights web application.

## Software Developer for CCExtractor

Google Summer Of Code 2017

05/2017 - 08/2017

Work From Home

- Developed Multi platform GUI using Nuklear Library in C.
- Wrote Autotools scripts to automate the build procedure.
- URL for pull request:
- https://github.com/CCExtractor/ccextractor/pull/794

## **ROLE OF RESPONSIBILITY**

## **Team Lead**

Smart India Hackathon 2017, final round

04/2017 Jaipur, India

- Upgraded StartUp India Android Application
- \* Redesigned UI, refurbished UX and fixed bugs.
- https://github.com/hackathonDND/StartupIndia

## **Organiser**

## **Programming Competetion**

Greater Noida, India

 Organised programming competetion in College on "Codechef" portal.

## PROJECTS/CONTRIBUTIONS

#### **Contributions**

LibreOffice (changes at gerrit.libreoffice.org)

- Fixed build issued caused by dedicated graphics on Laptop computers (Windows). Change #23144
- Added Oval shape transition variant and Oval (vertical) animation in LibreOffice Impress. Change #23510

#### **CCExtractor**

- Wrote Deb, Tar, Rpm package creation scripts for Linux and Autotools scripts to generate Makefile(s)
- \* Added OCR/Burned Subs extraction support for Mac.
- Commits:https://github.com/CCvExtractor/ccextractor/commits?author=techfreakworm

## **Projects**

### Face Recognition using Tensorflow.js

- Multi face face recognition with on-browser training.
- See live:

https://techfreakworm.github.io/face-recognition-tensorlow.js/

# Sentiment analysis of IMDB Movie Reviews

- Realtime comparision between different algorithms.
- · See live:

https://techfreakworm.github.io/MovieReview-SentimentAnalysis/

#### Quiz Master

- Angular JS and DotNet app to hold Quiz events
- https://github.com/techfreakworm/QuizMaster

#### **Alchem**

- Inventory and account management system for Pharmaceutical shops in JavaFX.
- https://github.com/alchemsynergy/alchem

#### **EDUCATION**

# B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

08/2014 - 06/2018

India

- Delhi Technical Campus, affiliated to GGSIP University
- Aggregate Percentage: 79.6 %

Languages/ Technologies

Python, Java SE, C# (DotNet), SQL, Vanilla JS (ES6), Angular 8, JQuery, Bash, C, HTML, CSS, Version Control Systems, Android Development, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Deep Learning;